{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Chicken", "optb": "Snake", "optc": "Swan", "optd": "Crocodile", "opte": "Frog", "ans": "A", "explanation": "All except Chicken can live in water."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Cap", "optb": "Turban", "optc": "Helmet", "optd": "Veil", "opte": "Hat", "ans": "D", "explanation": "All except Veil cover the head, while veil covers the face."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Kiwi", "optb": "Eagle", "optc": "Emu", "optd": "Ostrich", "ans": "B", "explanation": "All except Eagle are flightless birds."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Rigveda", "optb": "Yajurveda", "optc": "Atharvaveda", "optd": "Ayurveda", "opte": "Samveda", "ans": "D", "explanation": "All except Ayurveda are names of holy scriptures, the four Vedas. Ayurveda is a branch of medicine."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Curd", "optb": "Butter", "optc": "Oil", "optd": "Cheese", "opte": "Cream", "ans": "C", "explanation": "All except Oil are products obtained from milk."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Potassium", "optb": "Silicon", "optc": "Zirconium", "optd": "Gallium", "opte": "Germanium", "ans": "A", "explanation": "All except Potassium are metals used in semiconductor devices."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Tea", "optb": "Cinchona", "optc": "Rubber", "optd": "Cardamom", "opte": "Chalk", "ans": "E", "explanation": "All except Chalk are obtained from crops."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Hangar", "optb": "Platform", "optc": "Dock", "optd": "Park", "opte": "Bus stand", "ans": "D", "explanation": "All except Park are halting places of various transport means."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Sparrow", "optb": "Swan", "optc": "Parrot", "optd": "Koel", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Swan is the only water bird in the group."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Tall", "optb": "Huge", "optc": "Thin", "optd": "Sharp", "opte": "Small", "ans": "D", "explanation": "All except Sharp are related to dimension."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Pear", "optb": "Apple", "optc": "Litchi", "optd": "Guava", "opte": "Orange", "ans": "E", "explanation": "Orange is the only citrus fruit in the group."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Dagger", "optb": "Hammer", "optc": "Knife", "optd": "Sword", "opte": "Blade", "ans": "B", "explanation": "All except Hammer are sharp-edged and have a cutting action."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Kanpur", "optb": "Allahabad", "optc": "Varanasi", "optd": "Mathura", "ans": "D", "explanation": "All except Mathura are cities situated on the banks of Ganga river."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Oyster", "optb": "Clam", "optc": "Scallop", "optd": "Mussel", "ans": "C", "explanation": "All except Scallop live in shells."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Deck", "optb": "Quay", "optc": "Stern", "optd": "Bow", "opte": "Mast", "ans": "B", "explanation": "All except Quay are parts Of a ship."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Producer", "optb": "Director", "optc": "Investor", "optd": "Financier", "opte": "Entrepreneur", "ans": "B", "explanation": "All except Director spend money."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Tricycle", "optb": "Trident", "optc": "Trifle", "optd": "Tricolour", "opte": "Trilogy", "ans": "C", "explanation": "In all except Trifle, 'tri' indicates 'three'."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Chameleon", "optb": "Crocodile", "optc": "Alligator", "optd": "Locust", "opte": "Salamander", "ans": "D", "explanation": "All except Locust are reptiles, while locust is an insect."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Calendar", "optb": "Year", "optc": "Date", "optd": "Month", "opte": "Day", "ans": "A", "explanation": "All others are parts of a calendar."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Mumbai", "optb": "Cochin", "optc": "Kandla", "optd": "Mysore", "opte": "Vishakhapatnam", "ans": "D", "explanation": "All except Mysore are harbours."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Cumin", "optb": "Groundnut", "optc": "Cinnamon", "optd": "Pepper", "opte": "Clove", "ans": "B", "explanation": "All except Groundnut are spices."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Biscuits", "optb": "Chocolate", "optc": "Cake", "optd": "Bread", "opte": "Pastry", "ans": "B", "explanation": "All except Chocolate are baked items."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Sweep", "optb": "Wipe", "optc": "Scrub", "optd": "Wash", "opte": "Stain", "ans": "E", "explanation": "All except Stain are terms related to cleaning."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Coat", "optb": "Shirt", "optc": "Blouse", "optd": "Trousers", "opte": "Sweater", "ans": "D", "explanation": "All except Trousers are garments which cover the upper part of the body."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Asia", "optb": "Argentina", "optc": "Africa", "optd": "Australia", "opte": "Antarctica", "ans": "B", "explanation": "All except Argentina are continents, while Argentina is a country."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Japan", "optb": "India", "optc": "Sri Lanka", "optd": "New Zealand", "ans": "B", "explanation": "All except India are islands, while India is a peninsula."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Spectacles", "optb": "Goggles", "optc": "Binoculars", "optd": "Microphone", "opte": "Telescope", "ans": "D", "explanation": "All except Microphone are related to eyes."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Shehnai", "optb": "Bagpipe", "optc": "Flute", "optd": "Sitar", "opte": "Harmonica", "ans": "D", "explanation": "All except Sitar are wind instruments, while sitar is a string instrument."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Cheetah", "optb": "Lion", "optc": "Bear", "optd": "Tiger", "opte": "Leopard", "ans": "C", "explanation": "All except Bear belong to the cat family."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Sheep", "optb": "Gazelle", "optc": "Ibex", "optd": "Shrew", "opte": "Tapir", "ans": "B", "explanation": "All except Gazelle are animals found in the mountains."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Flood", "optb": "Hurricane", "optc": "Avalanche", "optd": "Earthquake", "opte": "Explosion", "ans": "E", "explanation": "All except Explosion are natural calamities."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Ant", "optb": "Bee", "optc": "Moth", "optd": "Midge", "opte": "Spider", "ans": "E", "explanation": "All except Spider are insects having six legs."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Flute", "optb": "Guitar", "optc": "Sitar", "optd": "Violin", "opte": "Veena", "ans": "A", "explanation": "All except Flute are string instruments."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Treachery", "optb": "Fraud", "optc": "Deceit", "optd": "Swindle", "opte": "Morbid", "ans": "E", "explanation": "All except Morbid are synonyms of 'deceit'."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Lima", "optb": "Algiers", "optc": "New York", "optd": "Tokyo", "opte": "Beijing", "ans": "C", "explanation": "All except New York are capital cities."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Reader", "optb": "Writer", "optc": "Printer", "optd": "Publisher", "opte": "Reporter", "ans": "A", "explanation": "All except Reader are persons involved in the preparation of a journal, newspaper or magazine."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Arrow", "optb": "Axe", "optc": "Knife", "optd": "Dagger", "opte": "Sword", "ans": "A", "explanation": "All except Arrow are used while holding in hand."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Feathers", "optb": "Tentacles", "optc": "Scales", "optd": "Pseudopodia", "opte": "Flagella", "ans": "A", "explanation": "All except Feathers are organs for movement in different organisms."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Dog", "optb": "Horse", "optc": "Goat", "optd": "Cat", "opte": "Fox", "ans": "E", "explanation": "All except Fox are domestic animals, while fox is a wild animal."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "House", "optb": "Cottage", "optc": "School", "optd": "Palace", "opte": "Hut", "ans": "C", "explanation": "All except School are dwelling places."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Physics", "optb": "Chemistry", "optc": "Geography", "optd": "Botany", "opte": "Zoology", "ans": "C", "explanation": "All except Geography are branches of Science."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Football", "optb": "Volleyball", "optc": "Cricket", "optd": "Chess", "opte": "Hockey", "ans": "D", "explanation": "All except Chess are outdoor games."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Trunk", "optb": "Tree", "optc": "Fruit", "optd": "Leaf", "opte": "Flower", "ans": "B", "explanation": "All others are parts of a tree."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Giraffe", "optb": "Hyena", "optc": "Deer", "optd": "Rhinoceros", "opte": "Zebra", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Hyena is the only flesh-eating animal in the group."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Poland", "optb": "Greece", "optc": "Spain", "optd": "Italy", "opte": "Korea", "ans": "E", "explanation": "All except Korea are European countries, while Korea is an Asian country."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Bajra", "optb": "Mustard", "optc": "Rice", "optd": "Wheat", "opte": "Barley", "ans": "B", "explanation": "All except Mustard are foodgrains, while mustard is an oilseed."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Cot", "optb": "Sheet", "optc": "Quilt", "optd": "Pillow", "opte": "Blanket", "ans": "A", "explanation": "All except Cot are parts of bed-spread."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Assassinate", "optb": "Kill", "optc": "Kidnap", "optd": "Stab", "opte": "Murder", "ans": "C", "explanation": "All except Kidnap are actions of killing."}, {"question": "Choose the word which is different from the rest.", "opta": "Doe", "optb": "Bitch", "optc": "Sorceress", "optd": "Drone", "opte": "Mare", "ans": "D", "explanation": "All except Drone are females."}]]}